You will never forget
The Alamo is a history, war, drama film directed by John Lee Hancock.
Based on the 1836 standoff between a group of Texan and Tejano men, led by Davy Crockett and Jim
Bowie, and Mexican dictator Santa Anna's forces at the Alamo in San Antonio, Texas.
Sam Houston, played by Dennis Quaid.
Davy Crockett, played by Billy Bob Thornton.
James Bowie, played by Jason Patric.
William Travis, played by Patrick Wilson.
Antonio Lopez de Santa Ana, played by Emilio Echevarría.
Joe, played by Edwin Hodge.
The Alamo is a 2004 American war historical drama about the
Battle of the Alamo during the Texas Revolution.
The film was directed by John Lee Hancock, produced by Ron Howard, Brian Grazer, and Mark Johnson, produced by Touchstone Pictures and Imagine Entertainment, and distributed by Buena
Vista Pictures Distribution, and starring Dennis Quaid as Sam Houston, Billy Bob Thornton as Davy Crockett, Jason Patric as Jim Bowie, and Patrick Wilson as William B.
The screenplay is credited to Hancock, Stephen Gaghan, and Leslie Bohem.
The film received mixed to negative reviews from critics and was a
box office flop, losing the studio over $146 million.
The film explores themes of texas, based on true story, uprising, alamo.
The tone is emotional.